# JOHN MAGUIRE FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

#### **SUMMARY**

It was during college when I discovered my passion for mathematics, and analytic problem solving in general, but I felt advancing further in the field would not provide me with a sufficient creative output. From there it was a long, diverse road that brought me to my current position. Through all of these experiences I learned many different things about myself, and found a love for coding. The ability to solve a problem in a multitude of different ways, with each solution having different merits really speaks to me, and I am really looking forward to turning this newfound passion into a lifelong career.

## **CONTACT**

 $\searrow$ 

jmaguire5588@gmail.com

0

johnmaguiredeveloper.com

**631-877-0533** 

8

132 Jefferson Street, Brooklyn, NY, 11206

#### **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES: Javascript, Ruby, HTML, CSS, SQL
MATHEMATICS: Calculus (through intro to Differential Equations),
Linear Algebra, Algebraic Structures, Complex Analysis,
Real Analysis, Discrete Mathematics with Combinatorics
FRAMEWORKS: Ruby on Rails, React, React Native, Sinatra, JQuery
TOOLS: Git, Heroku

in johnmaguire1 jm96441n

## **EMPLOYMENT**

#### Superfine

126 Front Street, Brooklyn, NY, 11201 Server · Sep 2009 to Feb 2016

Server at a farm to table restaurant. Menu changed everyday, which required me to adapt and be able to describe new dishes everyday to patrons.

## CL Design

20 Jay Street, Brooklyn, NY, 11201 Metal Finisher · Aug 2015 to Feb 2016 Worked in the fabrication of custom chandeliers. Finished and stained different types of metals.

Office Assistant  $\cdot$  Aug 2015 to Feb 2016

Assisted with various office tasks (editing product catalogs, uploading new photo's of chandeliers to the website, customer outreach).

Math Tutor New York, NY

Self-Employed · Sep 2007 to May 2015

Self-employed math tutor. Worked with children from first grade up through eleventh grade.

## **PROJECTS**

#### MyToiletPal

A web app that allows the user to see all public toilets around them, review public toilets, as well as add toilets that are not currently in our database. Built using Ruby on Rails for the backend, React for the webapp frontend, and React Native for the mobile app.

#### ICYMI (In Case You Missed It)

An IOS app, with a webapp component, that shows the user a searchable list of every business they pass throughout the day in order to help them find places they may have missed during their day. Built with Rails on the backend and React Native for the mobile app and React for the webapp frontend.

#### Yoda Know

A star wars themed Stack Overflow clone. Built with Sinatra for the backend and using |Query on the frontend.

## **EDUCATION**

Pace University
B.S. Mathematics 2010

### DevBootcamp

19 Week Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp 2016